## Zubair Ashfaque

## Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

System Analyst with 9+ years of experience in several industries. My journey from internet networks to neural networks is driven by my passion to learn. Looking to leverage my experience and knowledge as a Data Scientist or Machine learning engineer at your company.



- mianashfaque@gmail.com
- Dubai / Lahore, UAE / Pakistan
- in linkedin.com/in/zubair-ashfaque-ab100621

- +971501562039 / +923018480350
- zubairashfaque.github.io/
  - github.com/zubairashfaque

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### System Analyst

Jazz

07/2017 – Present Lahore

Jazz is a Pakistani mobile network and internet services provider

#### Tasks

- I worked as a System Analyst in the revenue assurance department, I balanced a swath of competing priorities, ranging from daily operations tasks and automation of alerts to fixing problems, incorporation new business controls, and developing new APIs.
- This role helped me to develop a wide-range understanding
  of telco fraud and revenue controls, improving my
  programming skills, planning skills, and debugging skills. It
  also gave me a chance to work on new technologies like
  HADOOP.

Contact: Muhammad Faizan Anwar – faizan.anwar@jazz.com.pk

# Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) Planning

Jazz

01/2017 - 07/2017

Islamabad

Task

 Design, implementation, deployment, and maintenance of middleware architecture integrated with CRM (Siebel), Electronic Financial Inventory Control System (EFICS), Billing System (Geneva) and Provisioning System (Comptel).

Contact: Jalal Shahid — jalal.shahid@guest.jazz.com.pk

## **Broadband Supervisor** PTCL

2009 – 2011 Lahore

PTCL provides telephone and internet services nationwide and is the backbone for the country's telecommunication infrastructure

#### Achievements/Tasks

 Configuring different ADSL routers & modems solving different problems regarding DSL and IPTV. Additional task was to develop and maintain the database of BCMS which was a complaint management system.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor in Telecom Systems**Beaconhouse National University

2005 – 2009

## **PROGRAMMING**

Python PyS

PySpark

SQL

TensorFlow

Pytorch

Keras

## **SKILLS**

Data Science, Machine Learning, Python Programming, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Convolution Neural Network, Artificial Neural Network, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, GCP

Coursera

## **LANGUAGES**

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

## SOFTWARE

IBM Cloud IBM Watson Studio Oracle RDB

Tableau Anaconda Zeppelin

Jupyter Notebook Apache Spark HADOOP

## **CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES**

Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai | Coursera IBM Data

Science by IBM | Coursera Certified Data Scientist |

DataCamp Machine Learning with TensorFlow on Google

CloudPlatform by GOOGLE | Coursera TensorFlow in

Practice by deeplearning.ai | Coursera